<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>&lt;/&gt; codeFright 🎃</title>
    <link>https://www.codefright.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on &lt;/&gt; codeFright 🎃</description>
    <image>
      <title>&lt;/&gt; codeFright 🎃</title>
      <url>https://www.codefright.com/static/logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.codefright.com/static/logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2025 codeFright 👻</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://www.codefright.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.codefright.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.codefright.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>Anu S Pillai Android | Kotlin | Flutter
✉️ anu_icloud@icloud.com | 📍 Bangalore, India
Summary Experienced Android and Kotlin developer with over 11 years of expertise designing, architecting and developing Android applications, SDKs and library projects. Extensive experience leading teams and delivering high-quality software solutions.
Successfully developed and published over 25 apps on PlayStore, including apps with over 100K downloads, such as South Indian Bank mPassbook, Scootsy (acquired by Swiggy), Revofit (a fitness/lifestyle app backed by Marico), Wellthy Care (a chronic disease management platform, acquired by TruDoc Inc.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="anu-s-pillai">Anu S Pillai</h1>
<p>Android | Kotlin | Flutter<br>
✉️ <a href="mailto:anu_icloud@icloud.com">anu_icloud@icloud.com</a> | 📍 Bangalore, India</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Experienced Android and Kotlin developer with over 11 years of expertise designing, architecting and developing Android applications, SDKs and library projects. Extensive experience leading teams and delivering high-quality software solutions.</p>
<p>Successfully developed and published over 25 apps on PlayStore, including apps with over 100K downloads, such as South Indian Bank mPassbook, Scootsy (acquired by Swiggy), Revofit (a fitness/lifestyle app backed by Marico), Wellthy Care (a chronic disease management platform, acquired by TruDoc Inc.), and Catch &amp; Win - Howzzattt (a 2D game developed using AndEngine for Toonz Animation India).</p>
<p>Passionate about learning and mastering new technologies and frameworks independently. Enjoys sharing knowledge through meetups, blogging, and open-source contributions. Would love to explore more of KMM and mobile LLMs.</p>
<h2 id="experience">Experience</h2>
<h3 id="tech-lead---apps-and-frameworks">Tech Lead - Apps and Frameworks</h3>
<p><strong>Borqs Software Solutions, Bangalore</strong> <em>(2023 - Present)</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Leading a team working on an array of inhouse as well as ODC projects involving Android, Kotlin, Flutter</li>
<li>Worked as an Android / Kotlin Tech Consultant for an AAOS - Kotlin project for Qualcomm Inc.</li>
<li>Lead a team designing and architecting a Kotlin MQTT Cloud Sync module + Flutter companion app for an overseas Android Automotive project</li>
<li>Currently working with Meta Inc. (Facebook) for developing a Flutter based cross-platform desktop project</li>
<li>Actively participate in code reviews and project architecture discussions. Conduct internal meetups to upskill and mentor developers</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="lead-software-developer---android">Lead Software Developer - Android</h3>
<p><strong>Wellthy Therapeutics, Bangalore</strong> <em>(2021 - 2023)</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Architected and developed Wellthy app and SDK for Android platform with 100K+ downloads and maintaining &gt;99% weekly crash free users</li>
<li>Lead developer responsible for architecting and developing new feature requirements</li>
<li>Worked on Improving app user experience and timely bug fixes which resulted in PlayStore rating going up from 3.5 to 4.6 in a year</li>
<li>Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop features that met business requirements</li>
<li>Led the team to brainstorm and implement code optimizations and features which led to a significant improvement in code reusability, modularity and maintainability</li>
<li>Helped the organization to achieve faster development goals by introducing code templates and generators</li>
<li>Overlooking the Sprint plans, Task prioritization and ensure timely sprint / task closure</li>
<li>Maintaining the team&rsquo;s performance scorecards, BvA analysis, setting and tracking quarterly goals</li>
<li>Lead the Wellthy SDK development team to develop and document SDK based on Wellthy Platform</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="senior-software-developer---android">Senior Software Developer - Android</h3>
<p><strong>Wellthy Therapeutics, Bangalore</strong> <em>(2017 - 2021)</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Architected and developed Wellthy app for Android platform</li>
<li>Developed and maintained mobile applications using Kotlin language</li>
<li>Bug tracking / Fixing and timely release and team management</li>
<li>Write and review test cases</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="senior-application-developer">Senior Application Developer</h3>
<p><strong>Scootsy (Acquired by Swiggy), Mumbai</strong> <em>(2014 - 2017)</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Led the team developing Android Apps like Scootsy, Revofit, Scootsy VMS from scratch</li>
<li>Developed and maintained mobile applications using Java</li>
<li>Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop mobile applications</li>
<li>Developer responsible for coordinating the project. Followed Agile / Scrum development methodology</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="junior-android-developer">Junior Android Developer</h3>
<p><strong>Simrge, Trivandrum</strong> <em>(2013 - 2014)</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Developed Android Apps like mParking Dubai, Howzzattt 2D Game using AndEngine, SIB mPassbook (Android + Blackberry), iCRM for vTiger</li>
<li>First Android Hire. Followed Agile development</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="education">Education</h2>
<h3 id="bachelor-of-information-technology">Bachelor of Information Technology</h3>
<p><strong>Anna University, Chennai</strong> <em>(2008 - 2012)</em></p>
<h2 id="skills">Skills</h2>
<h3 id="languages">Languages</h3>
<ul>
<li>Kotlin (Proficient)</li>
<li>Java (Proficient)</li>
<li>Flutter / Dart (Advanced)</li>
<li>KMM (Beginner)</li>
<li>Python (Intermediate)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/2369140/asp">Stack Overflow</a></li>
<li><a href="https://linkedin.com/in/anuspillai">LinkedIn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/anugotta">GitHub</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/as_pillai">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="https://codefright.com">Blog</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="notable-contributions">Notable Contributions</h2>
<h3 id="wellthy-care-wellthy-therapeutics">WELLTHY CARE (WELLTHY THERAPEUTICS)</h3>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=wellthy.care&amp;hl=en_GB">View on Play Store</a></p>
<p>Wellthy Care is the digital health coach that will help you manage diabetes, chronic kidney disease (CKD) and other such chronic conditions.</p>
<ul>
<li>Technologies used: Kotlin, MVVM, Hilt, Coroutines, Retrofit with RxJava for API calls, Realm, Espresso, JUnit, AWS Mqtt</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="scootsy-acquired-by-swiggy">SCOOTSY (ACQUIRED BY SWIGGY)</h3>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.antfarm.scootsy">View on Play Store</a></p>
<p>Scootsy is an intra-city delivery service in Mumbai that delivers from the best restaurants, food stores, book shops, toy stores, fashion outlets, gift shops, sport stores and more.</p>
<ul>
<li>Technologies used: Java, SQLite, Retrofit, Socket.IO, Firebase, GraphQL</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="south-indian-bank-m-passbook-android--windows-blackberry">SOUTH INDIAN BANK M-PASSBOOK (ANDROID / WINDOWS /BLACKBERRY)</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.southindianbank.com/content/viewContentLvl2.aspx?linkIdLvl2=16&amp;linkid=731">View Details</a></p>
<p>India&rsquo;s one of the first mobile passbook app. Track your SIB account transactions on the go. Developed for South Indian Bank. Developed for Android and Windows. Ported to Blackberry.</p>
<ul>
<li>Technologies used: Java, SQLite, Retrofit, C# (for Windows app)</li>
</ul>
<p>And Many More!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.codefright.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.codefright.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>FlipTimerView A customizable flip animation timer library for Android, developed in Kotlin.
Simple flip animation with customizable duration Support for days, hours, minutes and seconds http_cyclic_mocks A lightweight Dart library for mocking HTTP responses with Dio. Mock Multiple Responses for single route / endpoint.
Support for multiple responses per endpoint Cyclic response patterns Easy integration with existing Dio setup Perfect for testing and development KinderScript [Work in Progress] A simple terminal based child-friendly programming language for learning coding basics.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="fliptimerviewhttpsgithubcomanugottafliptimerview"><a href="https://github.com/anugotta/FlipTimerView">FlipTimerView</a></h3>
<p>A customizable flip animation timer library for Android, developed in Kotlin.</p>
<ul>
<li>Simple flip animation with customizable duration</li>
<li>Support for days, hours, minutes and seconds</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="http_cyclic_mockshttpsgithubcomanugottahttp_cyclic_mocks"><a href="https://github.com/anugotta/http_cyclic_mocks">http_cyclic_mocks</a></h3>
<p>A lightweight Dart library for mocking HTTP responses with Dio. Mock Multiple Responses for single route / endpoint.</p>
<ul>
<li>Support for multiple responses per endpoint</li>
<li>Cyclic response patterns</li>
<li>Easy integration with existing Dio setup</li>
<li>Perfect for testing and development</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="kinderscripthttpsgithubcomanugottakinderscript"><a href="https://github.com/anugotta/KinderScript">KinderScript</a></h3>
<p>[Work in Progress] A simple terminal based child-friendly programming language for learning coding basics. Developed completely in Kotlin.</p>
<ul>
<li>Simple syntax for kids</li>
<li>Built for educational purposes</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
